{"topic":"CSS","questions":[{"id":1,"question":"What does the '>' selector signify?","a":"That the element matched by the right hand side must be an immediate child of the element matched by the left hand side","b":"That the element matched by the right hand side must be a descendant at any level of the element matched by the left hand side","answer":"a"},{"id":2,"question":"Which of these correctly defines 'specificity'?","a":"The number of selectors involved in a CSS rule","b":"The weight given to a CSS rule based on the weighted values of the selectors involved","answer":"b"},{"id":3,"question":"What is a pseudo-class selector?","a":"A selector which applies to an element in a particular state","b":"A selector which applies to an element with a given class","answer":"a"},{"id":4,"question":"Which CSS properties make up the Box Model?","a":"Content width and height, and padding","b":"Content width and height, padding and border","answer":"b"},{"id":5,"question":"What does a 'reset' CSS file do?","a":"Forces all styles to be reset to null, thereby avoiding issues due to the varying default styles of browsers","b":"Provides a basic style guide for a site","answer":"a"},{"id":6,"question":"How does normalize.css differ from a 'reset' CSS file?","a":"It sets all styles to null, rather than providing default values","b":"It provides a set of reasonable default styling values, rather than setting all styles to null","answer":"b"},{"id":7,"question":"What are sprites?","a":"Multiple images stored as one, so that they are all loaded as a single image in a browser","b":"The individual icons used on a website, which each get stored and loaded separately","answer":"a"},{"id":8,"question":"What is the difference between 'inline' and 'block' display values?","a":"Block elements continue on the same line using only as much width as they need; inline elements use their own line and use the full width available","b":"Inline elements continue on the same line using only as much width as they need; block elements use their own line and use the full width available","answer":"b"},{"id":9,"question":"What is responsive design?","a":"Design which will fluidly respond to style correctly on any device","b":"Design which provides appropriate features and layout based on a predefined set of e.g. viewport sizes","answer":"a"},{"id":10,"question":"What is adaptive design?","a":"Design which will fluidly respond to style correctly on any device","b":"Design which provides appropriate features and layout based on a predefined set of e.g. viewport sizes","answer":"b"},{"id":11,"question":"Which of the following correctly describes SVG?","a":"It is a vector image format which retains its sharpness at any size","b":"It is a raster image format supported by IE8 and below","answer":"a"},{"id":12,"question":"What does the @font-face CSS rule allow you to do?","a":"Give standard web-safe fonts a custom name","b":"Use custom web fonts","answer":"b"},{"id":13,"question":"Which of these contains a valid attribute selector?","a":"a[href=value]","b":"a:href","answer":"a"},{"id":14,"question":"What does the term 'grouping' refer to?","a":"Using a number of selectors to apply styles to a single target element","b":"Using a comma-separated list of selectors to apply the same styles to multiple elements","answer":"b"},{"id":15,"question":"Which selector would you use to target an element with an ID of 'myId'?","a":"#myId","b":".myId","answer":"a"},{"id":16,"question":"What are pseudo-elements used for?","a":"Applying styles to an element in a particular state, e.g. hover","b":"Applying styles to a particular part of an element, e.g. styling the first letter of its content","answer":"b"},{"id":17,"question":"Which of these would be the correct notation for targeting a pseudo-element using CSS3 syntax?","a":"p::first-line","b":"p:first-line","answer":"a"},{"id":18,"question":"What is the z-index property used for?","a":"Controlling the vertical ordering of elements on the page","b":"Controlling the stack order of overlapping elements","answer":"b"},{"id":19,"question":"What is the difference between 'display: none' and 'visibility:hidden'?","a":"'visibility: hidden' hides the element while still allowing it to take up its space on the page, whereas 'display: none' hides the element without taking up any space","b":"'visibility: hidden' only hides the content of an element, whereas 'display: none' hides the entire element","answer":"a"},{"id":20,"question":"Which of these describe three valid techniques for clearing floats?","a":"Use a clearfix, float the parent element, or use a position property on the parent element","b":"Use a clearfix, float the parent element, or use an overflow property on the parent element","answer":"b"},{"id":21,"question":"If a parent element contains only floated child elements, what would its height be?","a":"Zero height","b":"The height of the tallest floated child element","answer":"a"},{"id":22,"question":"How would you write a comment in CSS?","a":"<!-- My comment -->","b":"/* My comment */","answer":"b"},{"id":23,"question":"Which of these CSS properties would you use to prevent your anchor links from being underlined?","a":"text-decoration: none","b":"font-decoration: none","answer":"a"},{"id":24,"question":"What does the 'initial' keyword do to a CSS property?","a":"Reset it to the default value defined by the browser","b":"Reset it to the default value defined by the CSS spec","answer":"b"},{"id":25,"question":"How would you restore a CSS property to the original default value defined in your style guide?","a":"Declare a new CSS rule repeating the desired default property","b":"Use the 'initial' keyword","answer":"a"},{"id":26,"question":"What would the selector 'img + a' do?","a":"Target an <a> element which is the immediate parent of an <img> element","b":"Target an <a> element which is the immediate sibling of an <img> element","answer":"b"},{"id":27,"question":"Given one <div> tag followed by three sibling <p> tags, which of these selectors would match more elements?","a":"div ~ p","b":"div + p","answer":"a"},{"id":28,"question":"Which of these would be the preferred method for overriding a CSS property?","a":"Using '!important'","b":"Using a CSS rule with a higher level of specificity","answer":"b"},{"id":29,"question":"What is a contextual selector?","a":"A selector addressing a specific occurrence of an element, where the styling is applied to only the last element in the selector pattern","b":"A selector addressing a specific occurrence of an element, where the styling is applied to all elements referenced in the selector pattern","answer":"a"},{"id":30,"question":"How would you set the text of an element to be uppercase using CSS?","a":"Using 'font-style: uppercase'","b":"Using 'text-transform: uppercase'","answer":"b"},{"id":31,"question":"How you implement multiple borders on a single element using just one CSS property?","a":"Using the 'box-shadow' property","b":"Using the 'border' property","answer":"a"}]}